national-accident-helpline.co.uk 2017-03-16

# Privacy Policy | National Accident Helpline

### National Accident Helpline Limited ("NAH" or "we" or "us" or "our") are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy.

This policy (together with our [terms and conditions](https://www.national-accident-helpline.co.uk/terms-conditions.html "Terms & Conditions") and any other documents referred to on it) sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us. Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it. By visiting our website or using our services you are accepting and consenting to the practices described in this policy.

For the purpose of the Data Protection Act 1998 (the “Act”), the data controller is NAH whose registered office is 1430 Montagu Court, Kettering Parkway, Kettering, NN15 6XR. Our registration number with the Information Commissioner’s Office is Z4979903.

Our nominated representative for the purpose of the Act is Jonathan White.

### 1\. Information we may collect from you

1.1 You may give us information about you:

1.1.1 When speaking with our call centre advisors or other members of staff;

1.1.2 When corresponding with us via letter, fax or email;

1.1.3 When filling in forms on our site http://www.national-accident-helpline.co.uk or such other website as may replace it from time to time (“our site”); and

1.2 We may collect the following information about you:

1.2.1 Your name; address; contact details such as email address and phone number; date of birth; personal description and photograph; insurance details; financial information; details regarding your health and injury and any other information relevant to your claim. It is important to National Accident Helpline that our service is accessible to all accident victims. Whilst we always endeavour to obtain consent from the injured party before processing personal data, this is not always possible (e.g. when the accident victim is a child, non-English speaker, elderly/infirm relative). In these cases, it will be necessary to take details from a third party.  Where appropriate, we will always ask whether the injured party has consented to the processing of his/her information.  This can be evidenced by call recordings and the details of both the caller and injured party will be documented on our IT systems;

1.2.2 Technical information, including the internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the internet, browser type and version, time zone setting, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform; and

1.3 Provided you have given the necessary consent when you spoke to us about your accident, we may receive information about you if you use the services of any other companies within our group of companies (which means our ultimate holding company NAHL Group PLC as defined in section 1159 of the UK Companies Act 2006);

1.4 Provided you have given the necessary consent to your solicitor, we may receive information;

1.4.1 from one of our panel solicitor firms or other person, firm or corporate entity (including insurance providers, medical practitioners, and costs draftsmen) dealing with your claim;

1.4.2 from any person, firm or corporate entity relating to your claim; and

1.4.3 from other third parties who may help us to process your enquiries

### 2\. What we do with your information

2.1 Provided you have given the necessary consent to National Accident Helpline, we will use your information:

2.1.1 to provide you with the information, products and services that you request from us. In particular, we may pass on your information to one of our panel solicitor firms so they can commence work on your claim if you have given them the consent to access the data given to National Accident Helpline. The data that we collect about you will be stored on our database and can only be accessed by our nominated panel solicitor firm if you give them access to that database.  Both we and the panel solicitor will continue to exchange information about you in order to update one another with further details about your claim (for example, any compensation you have received). We will use information provided by our panel solicitors to measure the quality of the service you receive and communicate with you. The solicitor’s firm will use information about you provided by us to manage your claim and measure the quality of the service you receive;

2.1.2 to provide you with information about other goods and services we offer that are similar to those that you have already purchased or enquired about;

2.1.3 to provide you, or permit selected third parties to provide you, with information about goods or services we feel may interest you;

2.1.4 to notify you about changes to our services;

2.1.5 to ensure that content from our site is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer;

2.1.6 to administer our site and for internal operations, including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, research, statistical and survey purposes; and

2.1.7 to measure or understand the effectiveness of advertising we serve to you and others, and to deliver relevant advertising to you.

2.1.8 We may share your personal information with any member of our Group.

2.2 Provided you have given us your fully informed consent in compliance with Data Protection Act 1998, Privacy and Electronic Communications Regulations 2003 (“PECR”) and ICO guidance on Direct Marketing, we may share your information with selected third parties including:

2.2.1 Our panel solicitor firms who deal with your claim, business partners, suppliers and sub-contractors for the performance of any contract we enter into with them or you;

2.2.2 Financial institutions, banks, credit and lending companies, debt management companies, marketing agencies and any other provider of goods and services that we think may be of use to you;

2.2.3 Advertisers and advertising networks that require the data to select and serve relevant adverts to you and others. We do not disclose information about identifiable individuals to our advertisers, but we may provide them with aggregate information about our users ). We may also use such information to help advertisers reach the kind of audience they want to target (for example, women in SW1). We may make use of the personal data we have collected from you to enable us to comply with our advertisers’ wishes by displaying their advertisement to that target audience].

2.2.4 Analytics and search engine providers that assist us in the improvement and optimisation of our site; and in order to provide better content and service, this site uses the Decibel Insight web analytics service. Decibel Insight may record mouse actions and scrolling movement, as well as basic interactions with website forms. We may share information about you with Decibel Insight. This data will not be used for any reason other than to perform services for us. By continuing to use this site you consent to our sharing your information with Decibel Insight. Decibel Insight does not track your browsing habits across other third-party websites. For more information about the data practices of Decibel Insight, please visit their [privacy policy](https://www.decibelinsight.com/privacy-policy/). You can opt out of Decibel Insight tracking by visiting – <https://www.decibelinsight.com/optout>

2.2.5 Analytics and search engine providers that assist us in the improvement and optimisation of our site; and in order to provide better content and service, this site uses Hotjar web analytics service. We are using the information collected by Hotjar service to improve our website, make it more user-friendly and monitor that it is performing correctly. Hotjar uses Cookies to obtain information regarding how visitors to this website are interacting with it. In particular Hotjar may record navigation through and interacting with the content on our website. Hotjar may also collect your device’s IP address (collected and stored in an anonymized format), device screen size, device type (unique device identifiers) and browser information, geographic location (country only), preferred language used to display the webpage, referring domain, pages visited, date and time when website were accessed. Hotjar may disclose collected information to third parties, including contractual partners.

If you do not want your activity on this website to be tracked by Hotjar, please opt out using this link: https://www.hotjar.com/opt-out  
<https://www.hotjar.com/opt-out>

To find out more about Hotjar’s privacy policy here: <https://www.hotjar.com/privacy>

2.3 We may disclose your personal information:

2.3.1 In the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we may disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets;

2.3.2 If we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply our terms of use [www.national-accident-helpline.co.uk/terms-conditions](https://www.national-accident-helpline.co.uk/terms-conditions.html "Home") and other agreements; or to protect the rights, property or safety of National Accident Helpline, our Group, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection.

2.4 We will keep your information for a period of 6 years (or such longer period as we deem reasonably necessary) after which we will take reasonable steps to remove and delete your information from our records and IT systems.

### 3\. Where we store your information

3.1 The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area (“EEA”). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy.

3.2 All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone.

3.3 Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

3.1 The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area (“EEA”). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy.

3.2 All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone.

3.3 Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

### 4\. Your rights

4.1 You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. We will inform you (before collecting your data) if we intend to use your data for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for such purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by informing our contact centre staff or by clicking the unsubscribe link at the bottom of all of our marketing emails You can also exercise the right at any time by contacting us at 1430 Montagu Court, Kettering Parkway, Kettering, Northants, NN15 6XR OR email us feedback@nahl.co.uk.

4.2 Our site may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks, advertisers and affiliates. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.

4.3 The Act gives you the right to access information held about you. Your right of access can be exercised in accordance with the Act. Any access request may be subject to a fee of £10 to meet our costs in providing you with details of the information we hold about you.

### 5\. Changes to our privacy policy

Any changes we may make to our privacy policy in the future will be posted on this page Please check back frequently to see any updates or changes to our privacy policy.

### 6\. Contact

Questions, comments and requests regarding this privacy and cookie policy are welcomed and should be addressed to National Accident Helpline Limited of 1430 Montagu Court, Kettering

Parkway, Kettering, NN15 6XR or emailed through to [feedback@nahl.co.uk](mailto:feedback@nahl.co.uk).

### Cookie policy 1. Information about our use of cookies

1.1 Our website uses cookies to distinguish you from other users of our website. This helps us to provide you with a good experience when you browse our website and also allows us to improve our site. By continuing to browse the site, you are agreeing to our use of cookies.

1.2 A cookie is a small file of letters and numbers that we store on your browser or the hard drive of your computer if you agree. You block cookies by activating the setting on your browser that allows you to refuse the setting of all or some cookies. However, if you use your browser settings to block all cookies (including essential cookies) you may not be able to access or use all or part of our site. For more information on cookies, their use and blocking them you may want to visit [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/). This link is provided for convenience only and we do not have any control over its content. We therefore make no warranties or representations as to the accuracy or completeness of any of the information appearing on that site or as to the suitability or quality of any of their products or services.

1.3 We need consent from you to receive cookies. When you first visit our website, you will be notified that if you continue to browse this site without changing your settings, we will assume that you have agreed to receive all cookies from our website

### 2\. List of cookies used on our site

Cookie Name | Cookie party | Expiry | Cookie Type  
---|---|---|---  
__gads | 3rd party | 2 years | Cloudfront  
is_returning | 3rd party | 5 years | Crazy Egg  
csrftoken | 1st party | 1 year | Website Cookie  
ULS | 3rd party | Session | Google  
PREF | 3rd party | Session | Google  
NID | 3rd party | 6 months | Google  
HSID | 3rd party | 10 years | Google  
APISID | 3rd party | 10 years | Google  
SS | 3rd party | 10 years | Google  
SID | 3rd party | 10 years | Google  
SAPISID | 3rd party | 10 years | Google  
SSID | 3rd party | 10 years | Google  
__utma | 3rd party | 2 years | Google  
__utmc | 3rd party | Session | Google  
__utmz | 3rd party | 6 months | Google  
__utmb | 3rd party | Session | Google  
HumanClickKEY | 3rd party | Session | Liveperson  
HumanClickCHATKEY | 3rd party | Session | Liveperson  
HumanClickSiteContainerID_36968323 | 3rd party | Session | Liveperson  
HumanClickACTIVE | 3rd party | 1 day | Liveperson  
mobile_detection | 1st party | Session | Mobile Detection  
nah_medtel | 1st party | 1 month | Website Cookie  
ysm_CK181QB1G7NDD4158K7AIH3OKVNUG | 3rd party | Session | Yahoo  
fpc10001487011762 | 3rd party | 1 years | Yahoo  
ywadp10001487011762 | 3rd party | 3 years | Yahoo  
SYSTEM_USER_ID | 3rd party | 4 years | Yahoo  
itsessionid10001487011762 | 3rd party | Session | Yahoo  
itvisitorid10001487011762 | 3rd party | Session | Yahoo  
_t | 3rd party | 10 years | Chango  
_rocket fuel | 3rd party | 1 year | Rocket Fuel  
_adroll | 3rd party | 5 years | Ad Roll  
  
### 3\. Cookies explained First party cookies

3.1 These cookies are set by the website itself and allows us to link the cookie with the website user. Where we refer to “Website cookie”in the table above, these cookies are used for essential website functionality.

### Third party cookies

3.2 We sometimes embed content from websites. As a result, when you visit a page with content embedded from such services, you may be presented with cookies from these websites. Our website does not control the dissemination of these cookies. You should check the relevant third party website for more information about these.

3.3 The definitions below apply to the third party cookies used in the table above:

3.3.1 “Google” – These cookies are used by Google to provide different Google services for the user and to collect anonymous data about the user.

3.3.2 “Liveperson”- Liveperson provides the live chat software. The cookies are set so the customers can use the live chat functionality.

3.3.3 “Mobile detection” – This cookie detects if the user is on a mobile device and then redirects them to a mobile friendly site.

3.3.4 “Yahoo tracking” – cookies set by Yahoo to track and analyse visitor activity

3.3.5 “Crazy Egg”- This cookie tracks whether or not a visitor is new or returning to particular website or page. Heat Mapping technology lets us know where people are clicking on our website.

3.3.6 “Cloudfront”- cookies set by Cloudfront to track and analyse visitor activity including visitor movement around the site.

3.3.7 “Chango tracking” – cookies set by Chango to track and analyse visitor activity.

3.3.8 “Ad Roll”- cookies set by Ad Roll enables us to present you with retargeting advertising on other sites based on your previous interaction with our website.

3.3.9 “Rocket Fuel” – cookies set by Rocket Fuel allow us to track and analyse visitor activity. We can then present you with display advertising on other sites based on your previous interaction with our website.  
Alternatively, when you visit a page on a website that’s part of Rocket Fuel’s network, you might get presented with a cookie and our display advertisement. Our website does not control the dissemination of these cookies. You should check the relevant third party website for more information about these.

### Social Sharing Tools

3.4 Any site with a social sharing button may set a cookie when you are also logged in to their service. We do not control the dissemination of these cookies and you should check the relevant third party website for more information about these.

### How to disable Flash Cookies

3.5 The Adobe website provides comprehensive information on how to delete or disable Flash cookies for all websites – see <http://www.adobe.com/devnet/security.html> for details. Please be aware that restricting the use of Flash Cookies may affect the features available to you for Flash based applications.
